Finding Aid for Bright Sheng Papers, 1962-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Audio recordings
  The Audio Recordings series is largely comprised of unpublished CDs of 27 performances featuring Sheng's work. It also includes an interview with Sheng broadcast on Voice of America and a published CD containing Sheng's piece The Stream Flows. The CDs are labeled simply as "CD #" but the description in the contents list below generally includes information on the date of the performances, the orchestra/performers and conductor, and the title of the pieces on the CD. Researchers should note that additional audio recordings, from Sheng's trip along Chinese portions of the Silk Road in the summer of 2000, are included in the Silk Road Trip series.
  - CDs
    - Unpublished recordings of Bright Sheng's music, 29 optical disks CDs
      - CD #1 (Box 16)
        - String Quartet No. 4. (Silent Temple) Premiere. April 19, 2000, 14:57
          (recorded at Eugen and Agnes E. Meyer Auditorium; Selected from Bill and Mary Meyer Concert Series of Freer Gallery of Art)
        - Four Movements for Piano July 23, 2002
          (Selected from FCM VII: American Music of the Past Fifteen Years of the Concert Series at 2002 Tanglewood Music Festival)
          - Movement 1, track 2, 3:50
          - Movement 2, track 3, 2:40
          - Movement 3, track 4, 2:58
          - Movement 4, track 5, 4:50
        - Three Songs for Violincello and Pipa July 23, 2002
          (recorded at Seiji Ozawa Hall, Tanglewood; Selected from FCM VI: American Music of the Past Fifteen Years of the Concert Series at 2002 Tanglewood Music Festival)
          - "Four Seasons", track 6, 1:49
          - "A Little Cabbage", track 7, 3:49
          - "Native Dance", track 8, 4:31
        - "A Tune from Childhood" (Saxophone version) March 9, 2004, track 9, 3:25
          (Recorded at Britton Recital Hall, Ann Arbor MI; the Premiere of Alto Saxophone Version; Selected from Brian Sacawa's Concert at the School of Music at the University of Michigan)
      - CD #2 (Box 16)
        - Bartok: Contrasts June 8, 2003
          (Bright Sheng conducting Chicago Chamber Musicians)
          - Track 1, 5:26
          - Track 2, 4:23
          - Track 3, 7:17
        - Three Songs for Violincello and Pipa June 8, 2003
          - "Four Seasons", track 4, 1:52
          - "A Little Cabbage", track 5, 3:06
          - "Native Dance", track 6, 4:32
        - Adams: Chamber Symphony (1992) June 8, 2003
          - Track 7, 8:30
          - Track 8, 9:42
          - Track 9, 7:08
      - CD #3 (Box 16)
        - Sheng: String Quartet No 3 (1993) June 8, 2003, track 1, 20:55
        - Sheng: Two Poems From The Sung Dynasty (1985) June 8, 2003
          - "Sheng Sheng Man", track 2, 3:05
          - "Chai Tou Feng", track 3, 11:27
      - CD #4 (Box 16)
        - Nanking! Nanking! (2000), July, 23 2002, track 1, 30:40
          (recorded at Seiji Ozawa Hall, Tanglewood, MA; Tanglewood Music Center Orchestra; Bright Sheng conductor; Selected from FCM VII: American Music of the Past Fifteen Years of the Concert Series at 2002 Tanglewood Music Festival)
        - Two Poems from the Sung Dynasty (1985) July 23, 2002
          (recorded at Sieji Ozawa Hall, Tanglewood, MA; Tanglewood Music Center Orchestra; Bright Sheng conductor; Selected from FCM VII: American Music of the Past Fifteen Years of the Concert Series at 2002 Tanglewood Music Festival)
          - "Sheng Sheng Man", tracks l-2, 4:07
          - "Chai Tou Feng", track 3, 10:35
      - CD #5 (Box 16)
        - H'un (Lacerations): In Memoriam 1966-1976 (1988), October 31, 1989, track 1, 22:16
          (recorded in Seattle by Seattle Symphony Orchestra, Jerry Schwarz conductor)
        - Nanking! Nanking! (2000) May 17, 2001, track 2, 28:44
      - CD #6 (Box 16)
        - China Dreams (1995) undated
          (recorded at Bowdoin Summer Festival by Bowdoin Summer Music Festival Orchestra, Bright Sheng conductor)
          - Track 1, 4:58
          - Track 2, 4:21
          - Track 3, 7:22
          - Track 4, 8:17
        - String Quartet No. 3 (1993) undated, track 5, 19:37
          (Recorded at Bowdoin Summer Music Festival)
        - Two Poems from the Sung Dynasty (1985) undated
          - Track 1, 3:09
          - Track 2, 10:10
      - CD #7 (Box 16)
        - Postcards (1997) undated
          (recorded in Seattle by Seattle Symphony Orchestra, Jerry Schwarz conducting)
          - Movement 1, track 1, 4:59
          - Movement II, track 2, 2:53
          - Movement III, track 3, 3:22
          - Movement IV, track 4, 5:07
        - Two Poems from the Sung Dynasty (1985) undated, track 5, 13:26
          - "Sheng Sheng Man"
          - "Chai Tou Feng"
        - String Quartet No. 3 (1993) undated, track 6, 19:39
      - CD #8 (Box 16)
        - Nanking! Nanking! (Premier) January 1, 2000, 26:38
          (recorded in Hamburg, Germany by North German Radio Symphony Orchestra, conductor Christopher Eschenbach; version with Gain Bootded on pipa)
      - CD #9 (Box 16)
        - Flute Moon (1999) Premier, undated
          (recorded by Houston Symphony Orchestra, Christopher Eschbach conductor)
          - Chi Lin Dance, track 1, 5:58
          - Flute Moon, track 2, 12:34
      - CD #10 (Box 16)
        - Boatman's Song (2003) April 25, 2004, 8:47
          (recorded in New York City by Young People Chorus)
      - CD #11
        - Tibetan Dance (2001) March 27, 2004
          (recorded at Chelsea Art Museum by St. Luke's Chamber Ensemble; Marianne Gythfeldt, clarinet; Melvin Chen, piano; Mayuki Fukuhara, violin)
          - Prelude, track 1, 3:32
          - Song, track 2, 2:43
          - Tibetan Dance, track 3, 6:05
      - CD #12 (Box 16)
        - 13 Ways of Looking at Goldberg (2003) May 2, 2004
          (recorded at Dalton Recital Hall, 2004 Gilmore Recital Hall; Gilbert Kalish piano; variations by Curtis-Smith, Higdon, Zupko, Walden, Sheng, Bermal, Del Tredici, Lerdahl, Bolcom, Foss, Gothoni, Hersch)
      - CD #13 (Box 16)
        - Tibetan Dance (2001) July 27, 2003
          (recorded at Santa Fe Chamber Music Festival, Bright Sheng Chamber Music concert; L.P. How, violin; Lori Lovato, clarinet; Bright Sheng, piano)
          - "Prelude", track 1, 3:56
          - "Song", track 2, 2:36
          - "Tibetan Dance", track 3, 4:39
        - Three Chinese Love Songs (1988) July 27, 2003
          (recorded at Santa Fe Chamber Music Festival; Evelyn Pollock, soprano; John Largess, viola; Bright Sheng, piano)
          - "Blue Flower", track 4, 1:32
          - "At the Hillside where Horses are Running", track 5, 1:24
          - "The Stream Flows", track 6, 3:55
        - Tibetan Dance (2001) July 27, 2003
          (recorded at Santa Fe Chamber Music Festival; L.P. How, violin; Lori Lovato, clarinet; Bright Sheng, piano)
          - "Prelude", track 1, 3:59
          - "Song", track 2, 2:44
          - "Tibetan Dance", track 3, 4:46
      - CD #14 (Box 16)
        - Red Silk Dance (1999) Premiere January 6, 2000, track 1, 15:46
          (recorded by Boston Symphony Orchestra, Robert Spano conducting; Emanual Ax, piano)
        - String Quartet No. 3 (1993), track 2, 19:33
      - CD #15 (Box 16)
        - Four Movements for Piano Trio(1990) April 4, 2003
          (recorded at the Pacific Rim Music Festival by the Empyrean Ensemble)
          - Track 1, 17:30
      - CD #16 (Box 16)
        - Two Poems for Violoncello and Orchestra (1998) March 12, 1999
          (recorded by the Singapore Symphony Orchestra, Lan Shui conducting; Yo-Yo Ma, Cello)
          - "Midnight Bells", track 1, 15:12
          - "Spring Dream", track 2, 8:32
        - Two Poems for Violoncello and Orchestra (1998) March 13, 1999
          (recorded by the Singapore Symphony Orchestra, Lan Shui conducting; Yo-Yo Ma, cello)
          - "Midnight Bells", track 3, 15:14
          - "Spring Dream", track 4, 8:37
      - CD #17 (Box 16)
        - Postcards (1997) September 28, 2003, track 1, 16:18
          (recorded by the Los Angeles Chamber Orchestra)
      - CD #18 (Box 16)
        - The Phoenix (2003) Premiere February 5, 2004, track 1, 24:38
          (recorded by the Seattle Symphony Orchestra, Jerry Schwarz conducting; Jane Eaglen, soprano)
      - CD #19 (Box 16)
        - The Song and Dance of Tears (2003) Premiere March 8, 2003, track 1, edited length of 25:18
          (recorded at Lincoln Center, New York City, by the New York Philharmonic, David Zinman conducting; Yo-Yo Ma, cello; Emanual Ax, piano; Wu Man, pipa; Wu Tong, sheng)
      - CD #20 (Box 16)
        - Nanking! Nanking! (2000), track 1, 28:47
          (recorded at the 2001 Winnipeg Music Festival by the Winnipeg Symphony Orchestra)
      - CD #21 (Box 16)
        - Tibetan Swing (2002)
          (recorded by the Brooklyn Philharmonic, Robert Spano conducting)
      - CD #22 (Box 16)
        - Three Tunes for Pipa and Erhu November 20, 2003
          (recorded at Trinity Center by Orchestra 2001)
          - Prelude, track 1, 2:03
          - Song, track 2, 3:20
          - Tibetan Dance, track 3, 4:21
        - Flute Moon (2001) November 20, 2003
          - Chi-Lin Dance, track 1, 5:55
          - Flute Moon, track 2, 12:02
      - CD #23 (Box 16)
        - The Silver River (1997 revised 1999), tracks 1-3, 67:36
          (recorded at the Spoleto Festival 2000 first edit)
      - CD #24 (Box 16)
        - The Silver River (1997 revised 1999), track 1, 74:00
          (recorded at the F.C.C. Festival 2000 first edit)
      - CD #25 (Box 16)
        - The Silver River (1997 revised 1999), track 1, 74:00
          (recorded at the F.C.C. Festival 2000 second edit: boosted and balanced)
      - CD #26 (Box 16)
        - H'un (Lacerations) (1988) October 11, 2002, track 1, 10:28)
          (recorded at Jordan Hall, NEC, by the Boston Modern Orchestra, Gil Rose conducting)
      - CD #27 (Box 16)
        - Stravinsky's The Song of the Nightingale (1917) January 17, 2003, track 1, 30:52
          (recorded in Lexington, Kentucky by the Lexington Philharmonic)
        - Flute Moon (2001) January 17, 2003
          - Movement I: Chi-Lin Dance, track 2
          - Movement II Flute Moon, tracks 3-8
      - CD #28 (Box 16)
        - Ravel's Mother Goose Suite (1911-1912) January 17, 2003
          - Concert Pre-Talk, track 1, 2:59
          - Mother Goose Suite Part I, track 2, 2:06
          - Mother Goose Suite Part II, track 3, 3:56
          - Mother Goose Suite Part III, track 4, 3:40
          - Mother Goose Suite Part IV, track 5, 5:04
          - Mother Goose Suite Part V, track 6, 7:05
        - China Dreams (1995) January 17, 2003
          - Track 7, 5:04
          - Track 8, 4:09
          - Track 9, 7:33
          - Track 10, 10:37
    - Interviews
      - CD #29 (Box 16)
        - Sound of Chinese Music November 2, 2002, November 9, 2002
          (Interview with Bright Sheng by Voice of America Radio, recorded in Washington, D.C.)
          - November 2, track 1
          - November 9, track 2
    - Commercial recordings
      - Kind of Colorful. Prestant Records. Featuring Xiang Gao, Violin; with Dr. Howard Watkins, Piano and Martin Katz, Piano.
        (A published CD containing The Stream Flows and program notes by Bright Sheng. Recorded August 1988)
- Student Works 1996-2004
  The Student Works, 1996-2004 series includes manuscript scores as well as both published and unpublished audio recordings (CDs) of works composed by Sheng's students. In accordance with provisions of the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act and University of Michigan policy, this series is restricted.
  [SR: Student educational records, restricted 75 years from date of creation]
  - Student Audio Recordings
    - Bridging the Pacific Rim: the Music of Chihchun Chi-sun Lee (Box 16)
    - Lokananta, for Japanese Gamelan and Symphony Orchestra, by Gabriel Ian Gould, 2000 (Box 16)
      (Performed by University of Michigan Gamelan Ensemble and Ann Arbor Symphony Orchestra)
      [Not for broadcast in any form]
  - Student Manuscripts (regular-sized) (Box 17)
    - Sam Davis Victor, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Armando Bayolo Songs to the Supple Suitor for medium voice and piano, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Paul Yeon Lee Silhouette for orchestra, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Joshua Palay Ode to Autumn, 1998 (Box 17)
    - Michael Djupstion String Trio, undated (Box 17)
    - Chi-Sun Lee, programs undated (Box 17)
  - Student Manuscripts (oversized) (Box 18)
    - Francesco Accolla, Ganga, to the children of Sarajevo, for orchestra, undated (Box 18)
    - Francesco Accolla Il Giardino di Hamdisi for voice and 16 players, undated (Box 18)
    - Gordon Beeferman Sonata Bombastica for Violin and Piano, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Derek Bermel Voices concerto for clarinet and orchestra, 1997 (Box 18)
    - David Schober Empty Shells, for violin and piano, 2000 (Box 19)
    - Gabriel Ian Gould Lokananta, for Javanese Gamelan and Symphony orchestra, 2000 (Box 19)
    - Pei Lu Rhapsody No.1, Dance of the Dragon, 2002 (Box 19)
    - Andre Myers Let Evening Come for Soprano and Chamber Orchestra, 2002 (Box 19)
    - Ozie C. Cargile II Once Upon the Sea, for alto Saxophone and String Orchestra, 2002 (Box 19)
  - Student Manuscripts (oversized)
    - Armando Bayolo Los Conquistadores, four poems for orchestra after Pablo Neruda, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Steven Simpson Into the Blue, for orchestra, 2003 (Box 20)
    - Joel Wm. Puckett Ping, Pang, Pong, 2004
- Silk Road Trip 2000
  The Silk Road Trip, 2000 series documents Bright Sheng's journey in the summer of 2000 to conduct ethnomusicological field work for the Silk Road Project. The trip covered several remote provinces in China, including Qinghai, where he got his start as a composer. Records in this series include Sheng's audio diary; recordings of local folk music; interviews, articles, and other writings about the Silk Road in general and the trip in particular; and numerous slides. The listing for CDs includes the dates of the recordings, the cities or areas in which the recordings were made and a brief description of the subject matter of the recording. Also, included in the "Silk Road Writings" folder is a printout of the website G. Schirmer created (also available at http://www.schirmer.com/silkroad/sheng/) as an companion piece to Sheng's trip. Also in diary format, it was compiled from email reports he sent while in China. Researchers may find it useful to also consult this piece while reviewing the slides or audio diaries from the trip.
  - Silk Road Audio Journal July-August, 2000, 4 optical disks CDs
    - CD #1 July 13-18, 2000 Beijing and Qinghai (Box 21)
    - CD #2 July 18-August 2, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Qinghia (cont.), Shaanxi, Gansu)
    - CD #3 August 3-13, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Gansu (cont.), Xinjiang)
    - CD #4, Aug 14-24 2000 (Box 21)
      (Xinjiang (cont.))
  - Folk Music Recordings July-August, 2000, 27 optical disks CDs
    - CD #5 July 14-16, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Danma Temple (7/14), Qutan Temple (7/16/), Ledu County, Qinghai)
    - CD #6 July 16-18, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Qutan Temple, Ledu County, Qinghai. Hua'er Singing at Hua'er Festival of Qutan Temple; Folk Songs Singing, Zang Opera, at Weinan Regong Art Festival.)
    - CD #7 July 16-18, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Datong county, Qinghai: Puppet Opera "West Journal of Emperor Tang"; Hua'er Singing; Drinking Songs.)
    - CD #8 July 16, 2000 (Box 21)
      (People's Park, Xining, Qinghai: Hua'er Singing; Banquet Songs; Pingtan Singing; Yutan singing; Drinking songs, etc.)
    - CD #9 July 20-21, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Xi'an, Shaanxi: Wanwan singing; Instruments--Yueqin, Yingxian, Banhu, Wanwan, Bangzi, Percussions.)
    - CD #10 July 22, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Xi'an, Shaanxi: Wanwan singing (cont.); Qing Opera at Circle City Park)
    - CD #11 (Box 21)
      (Xi'an Shaanxi: Shaanbei Folk Songs singing)
    - CD #12 July 24, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Yan'an Shaanxi: Suo Na performance; Shaanbei Ballad; Folk Songs.)
    - CD #13 July 24-30, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Sude, Shaanbei: Shaanbei Folk Songs)
    - CD #14 July 24-30, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Yuling, Shaanbei: Yuling singing I)
    - CD #15 July 24-30, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Yuling, Shaanbei: Yuling singing II)
    - CD #16, July 31. 2000 (Box 21)
      (Lanzhou, Gansu: Long Opera)
    - CD #17 August 2-10, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Wuwei, Lanzhou, Gansu; Folk songs singing by blind people; Lanzhou Guzi I)
    - CD #18 August 7, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Lanzhou, Gansu: Lanzhou Guzi II)
    - CD #19 August 3-12, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Chuannan county, Lanzhou, Gansu, Urumqi, Xinjiang: Yugu people's Folk Songs singing; Qiebiyate Mukam.)
    - CD #20 August 12-15, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Urumqin, Ahqi, Xinjiang: Mukam; Daolang Dance Mukam.)
    - CD #21, August 15th. 2000 (Box 21)
      (Ahqi, Xinjiang: The old person Magaty's singing; Duolang Mukam I)
    - CD #22 August 15-18, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Ahqi, Atushi, Xinjiang: Magaty's singing; Duolang Mukam II; Kilghiz Folk Songs singing at Atush)
    - CD #23 August 18-19, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Atush, Ahqi, Xinjiang; Kilghiz Folk Songs (cont.); Kumuzi Balad Singing by two old people at Ahqi.)
    - CD #24. August 22, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Ahqi, Xinjiang; Folk Songs singing by the old people Magaty from Ahqi)
    - CD #25 August 23-24, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Arharqi, Yining, Xinjiang: Kilghiz people's folk music; Kubuz Mukam; Xibo people's folk music; Yining Folk Songs. Music played by the Donbra)
    - CD #26 August 24, 2000 (Box 21)
      (Yining, Xinjiang: Folk Songs singing and played by the Donbra; Kubuz Mukam.)
    - CD #27, September, 4 2000 (Box 21)
      (Shandong: Lanshan Haozi (Labers Working songs); Wanglianmao Qiang)
  - Silk Road Slides, summer 2000
    The slides from the Silk Road Trip are arranged in approximate chronological order. The descriptions are derived from Bright Sheng's trip notes and comments. The slides are filed in album sleeves and individually numbered. The identifying number in square brackets indicates the sleeve number and slide number.
    - July 14-20, 2000 Residents of Qinghai Province, [1.1-5]
      - July 15, 2000 Tu people at Hu-Zhu county of Qinghai province, [1.5] (Box 21)
    - July 14, 2000 Dan Ma, a small town at Hu-Zhu county, people went to the first day of three-day annual Hua'er Festival, [1.6-9]
      - July 14, 2000 people, [1.8] (Box 21)
    - July 14, 2000 Young people singing during Hua'er Festival, [1.10-13] (Box 21)
    - July 14-20, 2000 Tu people having their traditional events, [1.14-18] (Box 21)
    - July 14-20, 2000 The scenery of Qinghai, [1.19-20] (Box 21)
    - July 17, 2000 Bright Sheng giving a lecture and a recital with his assistant, Annie Crawford, at the Musicians' Union, of Xining, Qinghai Province, [2.1-2.14]
      - Sheng giving a lecture and a short recital, [2.2-5] (Box 21)
      - Sheng with old friends who live in Xining, [2.6-14] (Box 21)
      - Left to right: Sheng's old friend, Sheng, and Crawford (assistant), [2.8] (Box 21)
    - July 12, 2000 Bright Sheng on the flight from Detroit to Beijing, [2.15] (Box 21)
    - July 13, 2000 Arriving at Xining airport in Qinghai from Beijing, [2.16] (Box 21)
    - July 18, 2000 Qu Tan Temple in Le Du County of Qinghai, [3.1-15] (Box 21)
    - July 18, 2000 The Yellow River., [3.16-18] (Box 21)
      (The river is along the way Bright Sheng drove through the mountain to Tong Ren County in the district of Huang Nan, Qinghai. The Yellow River was named after its color of mud, but here the water is crystal clear green. Qinghai is the riverhead for The Yellow River.)
    - July 14-20, 2000 The Scenery of Qinghai, [3.19-20] (Box 21)
    - July 21, 2000 Qinghai Lake, [4.1-7] (Box 21)
    - July 21, 2000 Bright Sheng and assistant Annie Crawford with Tibetan people who live on the side of Qinghai Lake, [4.8-9] (Box 21)
    - July 21, 2000 Bright Sheng riding along the side of Qinghai Lake, [4.10-12] (Box 21)
    - July 21, 2000 The scenery along the side of Qinghai Lake, [4.13-15] (Box 21)
    - ca. July 14-20, 2000 The mountain of Qinghai, [4.16] (Box 21)
    - July 21, 2000 Xining airport, Qinghai. Bright Sheng and his assistant Annie Crawford leaving Qinghai for Xi'an, [4.17] (Box 21)
    - July 22-24, 2000 Xi'an, Shaanxi Province, [5.1-2] (Box 21)
      (Qin opera performance, an old operatic form whose history can be traced back to the Qin dynasty (221-206 B.C.E). Qin opera, like all Chinese classical operas, combines music, dance, and drama.)
    - July 23, 2000 Qin opera performance at Xingqin Park of Xi'an, [5.3-10] (Box 21)
    - July 23,d 2000 The Scenery of Xingqin Park at Xi'an, [5.11] (Box 21)
    - July 23, 2000 Xi'an, Wan Wan Singing, [5.12-18]
      (A dying form of a local opera derived from the Shanxi puppet show. Four old people performed with unusual instruments. The music is completely in the style of calculated improvisation. The instruments are tuned differently, giving each player a greater freedom to form different melodic patterns.)
      - The percussion, one of the unusual instruments played by a Wan Wan Singing performer, [5.14-15] (Box 21)
      - The Moon Guitar played by a Wan Wan Singing performer., [5.16] (Box 21)
        (A hexagonal lute whose player wore a metal thimble on the index finger of his fingering hand to facilitate an elongated glissando effect, found also in Hawaiian guitar playing.)
      - The unusual mandolin, [5.17] (Box 21)
      - Northern Shaanxi (Shaanbei) Ballad, [5.18] (Box 21)
    - July 25, 2000 the scenery of Yan'an, Shaanbei, [6.1-10] (Box 21)
      (A cave town that used to be the military base of the Chinese Communist Party during the '30's and '40's. There are a few landmarks that recall the old days of the Red Army.)
    - July 25, 2000 Yan'an, a few well-known folk singers., [6.11-15-] (Box 21)
      (Yan'an, a few well-known folk singers of the area, who sang in highly decorative and sustained high falsetto notes with dramatic melodic patterns reflecting the landscape of this very mountainous region.)
    - ca. September 4, 2000 Shandong local opera, [6.16-19] (Box 21)
    - ca. July 26-27, 2000 Suide, [7.1-11] (Box 21)
      (A small museum of stone carving from the Han dynasty. These were from stone walls inside small important tombs. Carvings of musicians on the walls further convinced people that the instruments SHENG (mouth organ) and ZHENG (a koto-like zither) existed in China two thousand years ago. There were also drummers and elaborate dances carved on the wall.)
    - ca. July 25-29 2000 Folksong singing at Shaanxi Province, [7.14-15] (Box 21)
    - ca. July 26-28, 2000 Yuling, Shaanbei. Yuling Singing--a dying ballad form, [7.16-20] (Box 21)
      (The fascinating thing about this style is the performance practice discrepancy between the singing part (mostly male imitating female voices) and the instrumental accompaniment: the later remains in the southern style which is still evident in forms like Jiangnan Sizhu (southern chamber music ensemble playing), while the former is strongly influenced by the folksong style from the region. (See the Shaanbei parts of the Silk Road Journal by Bright Sheng))
    - July 29 2000 The scenery near to Xi'an City., [8.1-14]
      - The tomb of Fu Su, the first son of Qin Emperor, [8.1] (Box 21)
      - A local museum, [8.2] (Box 21)
      - Huaqingchi, a Palace that Emperor Li's wife used to have showers, [8.3-5] (Box 21)
      - The display of the museum, [8.6-11] (Box 21)
      - Tan San Cai, [8.12-14] (Box 21)
    - 2000 The scenery near the Huangdi Mausoleum, [8.15-20, and 9.1-8]
      - Huangdi Mausoleum, Shaanxi Province, [9.7] (Box 21)
    - Qian Ling, the tomb of Emperor Wu, the first female Emperor in Chinese History, [9.9-10] (Box 21)
    - July 29, 2000 Da Yan Ta, in Xi'an City, [9.11] (Box 21)
    - ca. September 4th. Lanshan Haozi (labor working songs), [9.12-9.15] (Box 21)